Guide to the Charles Hill Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Course Materials
  - Oratory in Statecraft
    - Edmund Wilson, "Changes in the American Style", undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Edmund Wilson, "Changes in the American Style", undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Engel, rhetoric of war, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt-rhetoric of disability, circa 2004 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Federalist papers (readings), 1788 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Geoffrey Hartman-Freud and rhetoric, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - George C. Marshall, undated (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - George P. Shultz, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - George W. Bush, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - George W. Bush-the State of the Union, 2003 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Handouts, 2007–2016 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Hillary Rodham Clinton, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Hitler's rhetoric (and the Kaiser's), 1970 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Homer-Iliad (embassy to Achilles), undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Inaugural addresses-Lincoln and Jefferson Davis, undated (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Lecture notes and "oratories", 2010–2014 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - John Brown, undated (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - John F. Kennedy, undated (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - John Paul II-address to 50th United Nations General Assembly, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - King James Bible, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Kipling-proofs of Holy Writ, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. (I have a dream), undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Michael Oakeshott, Talking politics, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Mussolini and the rhetoric of fascism, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Notes of oratory, 2008–2015 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Patton, speech to third army (1944), undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Plato, Phaedrus (James Boyd White), undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Plutarch (Demosthenes and Cicero), undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Poe, Edgar Allen, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Rhetoric, Adam Smith, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Rhetoric, Boutros-Ghali's Unvanquished, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Rhetoric, Bush on China, 2005 November (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Rhetoric, confederate rhetoric, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Rhetoric, extracting policy positions using words as data, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Rhetoric, Hobbes and the rhetorical tradition, undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Rhetoric, Library of Congress presidential speeches (cd), 2005 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Rhetoric, Machiavelli, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Rhetoric, "Malaise" revisited; Jimmy Carter and the crisis of confidence, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Rhetoric, Proust, undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Rhetoric, realism and rhetoric in international relations, undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Rhetoric, Richard Weaver, undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Rhetoric, rhetorical investigations of Robert Frost, undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Rhetoric, "Tone" (Jonathan Bishop on Emerson), undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Rhetoric, Watt, "The first paragraph of the ambassadors", undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Rhetoric, Whitman, leaves of grass, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Rhetoric, Wilson's revolutionary rhetoric, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Rhetorics of classical learning, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Rhetoric of foreign aid, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Richard Weaver, "The Power of the Word", undated (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Richard Weaver, "Two Orators", 1987 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Rivets in Ecclesiastes, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Robespierre, speeches 1793-1794, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Syllabus and notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - A theory of international rhetoric, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Wayne booth on rhetoric, undated (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Whitman, leaves of grass (Matthessen, "A language experiment"), 1941 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Winston Churchill (1897-1963), 1974 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Woodrow Wilson, "The new freedom" (1918), undated (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Revolution
    - American revolution, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Arendt, on revolution, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - English revolution, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - French revolution, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Horckheimer & Adorno, dialectic of enlightenment, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Nee and Peck, "Why Uninterrupted Revolution", undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Negri empire, Hardt multitude, 2001–2004 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Burke and French revolution, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Notes on revolutions, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Shanghai revolution II (Marx, Lenin, Mao), 2004 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Revolution (syllabus), 2004 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Revolution IV (capitalism), 2004 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Taiping rebellion, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Thomas Kuhn, "Structure of scientific revolutions", 2005 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Shanghai
    - Bibliography, 2003–2004 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Books, 2004 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Chiang Kai-Shek and Soong Meiling, 2003 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - China and Collective Sy (Shanghai Baby 1937), undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - China's apology diplomacy, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - China articles-British Petroleum, 2004 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Chinnery and Lam Qua, Nam Qua, Hou Qua, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Confucius, Analects, 1981–2004 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Confucius and democracy (and conservatism today), 1995–1996 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Confucius in the Cultural Revolution (Charles Hill and architecture exhibition), 1996 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Course pack, 1981–2001 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Course reader, 1946–2001 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Course reader, 1946–2001 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Diplomacy in medieval inner Asia, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Films, 2003–2004 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Gibbon in China, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - High colonial era, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Hill, "The Cultural Revolution in the provinces", 2003 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Images/clothes/styles, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Images, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Japan moves into China (1931-1945), 2004 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Jews in Shanghai, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Jos Levenson on Taiping, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Kuo Mo-Jo and the creation society, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Law, "Chinese international law terms", undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Literature, undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Maps, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Maps (Yeh, wartime Shanghai), 1998 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Maxtor in China, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Model settlement, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Morning in Shanghai/Charles Hill on Erh-fu, undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Opening of China I, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Opening of China II, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Overview notes, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Paris of the orient; New York of China, undated (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Perry opens Japan, undated (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Published materials, 1932–2004 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Publish materials on Chinese foreign relations, undated, 1965-1979 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Regulating sex in Shanghai, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Rowing in Shanghai, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Shanghai today, 2004 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Spring term 2005 notes (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Syllabus and course readings, 1995–2004 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Taiping rebellion and Shanghai, 2004 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Whitson encirclement campaigns, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - World city, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Barber, Fall of Shanghai OPT, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Bergère, "The Other China" Shanghai from 1919-1949, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Buss, People's Republic of China and Richard Nixon, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Clifford, Spoilt Children OPT, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Cooke Johnson, "Shanghai: An Emerging Jiangnan Port" OPT, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Deakin and Storry, Sarge, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Gaulton, "Political Mobilization" OPT, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Hill, "Fighting Stories", 1996 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Hill, "Introduction", 1971 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - L. C. Johnson, "Shanghai: An Emerging Jiangnan Port", 1993 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Lu, Beyond the Neon Lights OPT, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Mann, About Face, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Martin, Shanghai Green Gang OPT, 2004 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Murphy, Shanghai, Key to Modern China, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Nee, "Shanghai in the Cultural Revolution", 1973 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Nee, "Shanghai in the Cultural Revolution" OPT, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Prasso, "Salvaging Jewish Heritage", 2004 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Ristaino, Port of Last Resort, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Ristaino, Port of Last Resort OPT, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Ristaino, "Street Names", 2001 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - "Joint Communique" in Russell, The "Why" of Nixon's Trip, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Schwartz, Chinese Communism, 1951 (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Spence, Search for Modern China, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Spence, Search for Modern China, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Teng and Fairbank, China's Response to the West, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - Treaty of Nanking 1842, 1921 (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Yeh, "Shanghai Besieged", 1998 (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Yeh, "Struggle to Survive" OPT, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Strategic American Fictions
    - The American house images: Mount Vernon - the gas station, 2012 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Backup notes for Strategic American Fictions - decadence, 2000–2012 (Box 35, Folder 2-3)
    - "Bawn" Guilford, Connecticut, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - The Bear, 2003–2009 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - The Bear - images, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Course proposal form, 2009–2010 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - CSNS (consciousness), 2012 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - D. H. Lawrence, Studies in Classic American Literature, 2010 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Faulkner (The Bear) fictive architecture, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Gatsby images, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - The Great Gatsby, 2012 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - HUMS 313 (class notes, mini-lectures), 2012 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Invisible Man, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - James - Adams (images), Undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Kingston, Tripmaster Monkey, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - The Last of the Mohicans, 2012 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - The Last of the Mohicans - images, Undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Leaves of Grass, 2012 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Moby Dick, 2012 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Moby Dick - images, Undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - On the Road, 2012 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - On the Road - images, Undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Prospectus, American epic, 2013 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Syllabus, midterm, and notes, 2011–2012 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - The Scarlet Letter, 2012 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - The Scarlet Letter - images, 2012 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin (and Americo-Liberian houses), 2005–2012 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Walden, 2012 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Walden - images, Undated (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Whitman, 1961–2010 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Strategies of World Order
    - Strategies of World Order, 2009–2015 (Box 37, Folder 1-4)
- Research Materials and Subject Files
  Series III comprises research materials and subject files. These files were complied by Hill and used as research for talks, writings, and courses; they also functioned as general reference files on topics of interest to Hill. Many of these files consist of published materials—either articles, chapters, and clippings Hill copied or removed from publications—but also include correspondence, notes, and photographs. A few folders contain talks and lectures given by Hill.
  Series III is arranged alphabetically
  - General
    - The 100 Most Influential Books and best poems 1940-1990 (Times Literary Supplement), 1995 October 6 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - "A Crowd Can Empty a Stadium…", 1997–2000 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - "A Yale Education", undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Accounting, 2002 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Adam Smith (Paul Solman), 2008 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Adda Bozeman, 1989–2000 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Altered Strategic Landscapes conference, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - American civilization, 1990–2003 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - American exceptionalism, 2008 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - American Foreign Service Association proposed Master's degree--Charles Hill comments, 2010 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - American grand strategy=globalization, 2016 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - American identity: fragmentation, 2016 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - American literature quiz (cultural literacy), undated (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Annotated articles on tyranny, European Union, and United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, 2013–2016 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Annapolis process (Charles Hill at Slifka June '07), 2007–2008 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Anti-ballistic missile treaty, 1999–2000 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Anti-semitic doggerel, 1781 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Antisemitism (Momigliano), 2011 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - April Glaspie - Saddam Hussein, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Area studies, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Asia and Democracy, 1993–1995 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Assumptions of 1991 seen in 1999, 1991–1999 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Bad review, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - "Beauty, Brains and Brawn" (New Haven Lawn Club), undated (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Berkeley (1685-1793), 1995 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Berkeley College fellows, 1994–2000 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Berkeley College commencement, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Bill Buckley Niebuhr Forum, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Bio--Charles Hill, undated (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Bio sketches (books of…), 2013 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - "Bluespeak", 1994 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - The Boland Amendment, 2016 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Book and Snake, 2011–2016 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - Books from 5147 Cathedral Avenue NW, undated (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - Books for "Master's Shelf"--Berkeley College, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 35)
    - Boswell's Johnson, 1916–2005 (Box 38, Folder 36)
    - Broch--The Death of Virgil, 1966–2000 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Broch conference, 2003–2004 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Browning, 2012 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Bryn Mawr, 2003–2006 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Buddhism in Tibet, 2008–2012 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "Building the Epic: American Literary Classics and their Successors", 2013 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Bureaucracy, 2001 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Caesar--opening pages of the Gallic Wars, 1974–2001 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Calhoun College: renaming, 2016 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Calvin and Hobbes, 2000–2009 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Careers, 1994–2002 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Cassirer, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - The Cathedral and the Cube, 2004–2006 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - CH (Charles Hill) and lost causes, 2009–2010 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - CH (Charles Hill): copy of a map in an edition of Swift's Gulliver Travels, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - CH (Charles Hill) charts and strategic 1 pagers, 2005–2010 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - CH (Charles Hill) lecture for Don Kagan, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - CH (Charles Hill) "Master's Class", 2012 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - CH (Charles Hill) on grand strategy, 2017 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - CH (Charles Hill) resume and CV, 1997–2012 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - CH (Charles Hill) Uighur article, 2009 (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - "The Challenge of Governing over Diversity in an Age of Transparency", 2014 (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Charles Hill and Boutros Bouros-Ghali papers at Hoover, 1998–1999 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - Chart: all major wars, 2012 (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Chaucer--"The Knight's Tale", 2003 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - China, 1997–2003 (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - China-India: economic integration?, 2010 (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - China and Sea Power (Lao Ts'an), Undated (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - China "White Paper", 2000 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - Civilization (birth, marriage, death), 2004–2010 (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - The Civilization Theme (Rome), 2005 (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - Clippings/articles on Charles Hill, 2012–2015 (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Cold War chart, 2012 (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Committee on Social Thought, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - Conrad, 2006 (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - Conrad, the secret agent, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - Contents--Prologue: Books of the Red Chamber, 2009 (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - Crisis and Ideas, 2011 (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - Cuba/Cessina, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 39)
    - Dante (miscellaneous), 1995–2002 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Dante De Monarchia, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Dante on Acquinas and Bonaventure, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - David Jayne Hill, 1906 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - David Stacton, 1968–2010 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Diplomacy: the Macartney mission to the Ch'ien Lung emperor, 1790 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Diplomatic memory, 1994–2012 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Diplomacy in literature, 1986–2003 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Diplomacy library--Charles Hill's office at Hoover, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Don Quixote (Cave of Montesinos), undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Dostoevsky "Grand Inquisitor", 2002 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Duke University (democracy ancient and modern), 2011–2017 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Einstein at NAS (National Academy of Sciences) (Charles Hill), 1990 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Elie Kedourie, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Elizabethan Club at Yale, 2000–2005 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Elkon Basilike, 1957–2006 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Empire--rhetoric of empire, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - English Revolution, 2005 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Essays on Dante, 1954–2000 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - The Europeanization of America, 1998–2001 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Ex-ambassador letters, 2005 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Faust II (Helen), 1996–2005 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Final class spring (review of social thought) - INRL 695, GLBL 895, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Franco-Prussian War, 2004–2005 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Frayn Copenhagen, 1995–2005 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Gaza panel, 2009 February 26 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - George Agnew Chamberlain, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - George Eliot, Daniel Deronda, 2007 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - George Shultz on his memoirs (and notetaking), 2003 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Gertrude Stein, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Gertrude Stein: The Mother of Us All", 1934–2005 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Gibbon - Grand Strategy/International Studies/Directed Studies, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Gibbon/reindeer/letter to Wall Street Journal, 2006 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - The Grand Books, 2001 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Greene, Graham, The Quiet American, 1858–2003 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Grimmelshausen: Simplicissimus, undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Grove Street Cemetery, 2009 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - GS (Grand Strategy): Middle East - Grand Strategy's greatest challenge (lecture), 2002 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - GS (Grand Strategy) Sleeper, 2007 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Gulliver's Travels, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Hannibal (Elizabeth Ralph), 2010 November 15 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Haiti, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Hawthorne, Nathaniel, The Marble Faun, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Hegel (and the state), undated (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Heidegger, undated (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Heidegger: letter on humanism; Derrida: Plato's Pharmacy, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Henry Adams, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Henry Adams, 1981–1995 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Henry Adams' diplomacy, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Hiawatha, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - The Hotel and the Mosque, undated (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - How to Deal with Catholics - model United Nations, 2011 January 21 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Howie Schaffer's bunker, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Humanities, 2013 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Ian Watt - first paragraph of The Ambasssadors, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - India (British Petroleum), 2007 November 26 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "In Moscow, a New Eurasianism", 2014 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - International system(s) - Schroeder on 19th century, 2006 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - IS (International System) advisors (Taming the Prince), 1994 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - IS (International System) exercise: Singapore caning, 1990–1994 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - IS (International System) Pope and the Polis, 1995–2002 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - IS (International System) - The UN: What is it?, 1991–2002 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - "Jazz Strategy", 2004 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Jerusalem (riverbed), 2000 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Joe Sisco - Aide Memoire, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Joe Sisco's Aide Memoire, Circa 1960s (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - John Lewis Gaddis, notes on White House meeting, March 21 2006 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Just war theory (Augustine - Aquinas), 1999 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Kafka, The Castle, 2008 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Kalaish Mahapatra (see also notebook for May 2000) (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Kant (philosophy), 2001 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Ken Miller's "Murphy's Maxims" (KM killed in fall from mountain in Colombia 2003), 2002 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Kissinger (and Kissinger seminar at Library of Congress) 29 May 2003, 1996–2003 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Kosovo War, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Landscape, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Latour, 2014–2016 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Leo Pasvolsky (1893-1953), 1953–1993 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Letters on Leo Strauss, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Liberia, 2006 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Library of Secretary of State - Caesar's Gallic War, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - "The Limits of Universalism," speech by Henry Kissinger, 2012 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Lincoln/Faulkner: The Southern Gettysburg Address, undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Longfellow's Dante, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Louis Auchincloss, 2009 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Louis XIV, 2005 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Mace & Chain, 1997–2005 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Management consultancy, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Manet, undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Manifest destiny, 2005 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Manuscript on Freud, The Importance of Untenable Theories, 2010–2011 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
    - Manuscript on Freud, The Importance of Untenable Theories, 2014 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Marriage talk (Mace & Chain), 2004–2005 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - ME (Middle East) ending - Seven Pillars, 2007 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "The Meaning of East and West", 1960 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Means of Avoidance" (of engagement with world problems) sanctions, human rights, no to nation-building, et cetera, 1998 June (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Melville's Clarel Lynch's Jordan and Dead Sea, 1850 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Metahistory - Negri, undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Middle East: Charles Hill structure for new talks (to Abrams National Security Council), 2007 July (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Middle East chart (since 1924), 2012 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Milton: Samson agnostics, 2002–2006 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "Minsky's Moment" - The Economist, 2016 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Model UN at Yale - the global situation, 1980 September 22 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Modernism (Berman) from Yale Law Journal and Humanities, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Moyar, Triumph Forsaken - Charles Hill on Vietnam War, 2007 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Muriel Spark, The Mandelbaum Gate, undated (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Naval gunfire (continuous aim), undated (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Nazi rise, 2007 (Box 44, Folder 19)